emerson.edu 2015-09-11

# Emerson College Privacy Policy | Emerson College

Emerson College is respectful towards the preservation and protection of the privacy of those individuals who visit its websites. It is possible to visit Emerson’s websites without self-revealing any personal information. There are, however, certain features and advanced functions on Emerson’s websites, for which it is necessary that Emerson requests and receives personal information from the visitor, in order for the features and functions to be properly utilized. Should you decide to provide Emerson College with personal information, the College will limit the use of your personal information to College business and will not disclose it to persons or entities unaffiliated with the College unless

  * You have expressly granted your permission to do so, or
  * Disclosure is necessary to enforce College policy, or
  * The College is required to disclose in order to comply with State law, Federal law or other legal process.

####  I. Information Gathering

Emerson College may use or disclose your IP address, and data connection-specific information, to help us diagnose problems with our servers and to administer our websites by identifying

  * Which parts of our site are most heavily used, and
  * Where our audience comes from, both internal and external to the Emerson College data network.

####  II. Use of Cookies

Cookies are text files stored on computers to enhance the usability and regular operation of a website. Emerson College may use cookies to store information during and after an individual accesses Emerson websites. The use of cookies enables Emerson to tailor the use of our websites to individual visitors, and to tell if individuals have visited us before so we can be aware of an individual’s choices and interests the next time they visit. Any information you choose to provide may be stored in a cookie.

Emerson College may also use cookies to deliver online advertisements to previous visitors to the Emerson.edu domain. The techniques that our digital advertising partners employ do not collect personally identifiable information. Your web browser can be configured to refuse cookies or to notify you when an Emerson College website attempts to send you a cookie, however, making this choice could detract from the usability of certain Emerson College websites and prevent targeted messaging through digital advertising.  

####  III. Individual Accounts

Certain Emerson College websites allow individuals to create and maintain individualized accounts. Where these sites are concerned, individuals have the responsibility of maintaining the confidentiality of their accounts and passwords, and for restricting access to their computers. Individuals agree to accept responsibility for all activities that originate from their accounts.

####  IV. Security Measures

Emerson College follows industry-standard security measures, to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.

####  V. Third-Party Linked Sites

As a courtesy, Emerson College websites include links to third-party websites. If you use these links, be aware that Emerson College’s Privacy Policy does not apply to such third party websites. You use these third-party websites at your own risk and you should review the applicable terms and policies, including privacy and data gathering practices, of any site to which you navigate from a third-party link on an Emerson College website.
